Saurabh Mishra

Phone: 9205319410/9717167028

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saurabh-mishra-2628a29b/

Email: saurabhm399@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/iamsaurabhm

Summary

I have 7 years of overall experience in IT in which 2+ years in python. Currently working as a Python Developer in Innefu Labs Pvt Ltd, Delhi. Here, at Innefu, I am responsible for building ETL pipelines using python, pandas and Pyspark.

Skills

Technologies/Tools: Python, Pandas, Pyspark, SQL, ETL, Numpy, API, BeautifulSoup, VS Code

DBMS: Neo4j, MySQL **Cloud:** AWS (Glue, EC2, S3)

Work Experience

Innefu Labs Pvt Ltd, Delhi - Python Developer

2022 November - PRESENT

- 1. Creating ETL pipelines to acquire data from different sources (structured and unstructured) using BeautifulSoup and Python.
- 2. Designed and implemented real-time data pipeline to process unstructured, semi-structured and structured data from different data sources using Python, Pandas and Numpy.
- 3. Worked with clients to understand their needs to improve, maintain existing data pipelines.

Felcorp Paraplanning, Chandigarh - Python Developer

July 2021 – October 2022

- 1. Debugging and Customizing Web Application, adding and removing fields in application according to clients' needs.
- 2. Monitored and maintained operational readiness of application.
- 3. Collaborated with the team to verify correct implementation of software.

AU Small Finance Bank, Jaipur — IT Executive

October 2018 - March 2019

- 1. Worked on CRM to manage company's relationship and interaction with customers.
- 2. Installing and configuring new servers, workstation and other IT equipment.
- 3. Provide technical support, advice to corporate IT team.
- 4. Manage data/ System backup, migration and disaster recovery.

Agile Cloudtech Ltd, Dehradun – Web Developer

June 2016 – July 2018

- 1. Creating website layout/user interfaces by using standard HTML/CSS.
- 2. Integrating data from various backend services and databases.
- 3. Responsible for maintaining, expanding, and scaling our site. Managing front-end and back-end website development.
- 4. Troubleshoot and resolve website problems, Collaborate with members of creative team.

Hemogenomics Pvt Ltd, Delhi – IT Admin

June 2014 – July 2016

- 1. Upgrading, installing and configuring new hardware and software to meet company objectives.
- 2. Creating user accounts and performing access control.
- 3. Performing diagnostic test and debugging procedures to optimize computer systems.
- 4. Keeping up to date with advancements and best practices in IT Admin.

Projects

- 1. Currently working on a project of Defence Ministry to create ETL pipeline for their unstructured data (docx, pdf) and ingest it into neo4j (NO SQL Database) database.
- 2. Worked on a project for NIA to create ETL pipeline to extract data from one source and ingest to other source after transformation.
- 3. In previous company created a leave management system.

Education | Certification

Btech in Information Technology from Lovely Professional university

Neo4j Certified Professional

Python certification from BigdataFactory

Machine Learning certification from ISRO